<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <!--
--><item><title>The Arnolfini Portrait by Jan van Eyck (1434)</title><link>https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Jan_van_Eyck_-_Arnolfini_Portrait.jpg</link><description>The Arnolfini Portrait is a groundbreaking work in the history of Northern Renaissance art. Created by Jan van Eyck, it is one of the earliest examples of oil painting and showcases remarkable attention to detail and realism. The painting is filled with symbolism, from the mirror reflecting the scene to the presence of everyday objects, which invites viewers to ponder the nature of marriage, wealth, and status during the 15th century. Its significance also lies in its innovative use of perspective and light, influencing future generations of artists.</description><derivativePrompt>Create an artwork that reinterprets 'The Arnolfini Portrait' in a modern context, incorporating contemporary symbols of love and partnership while maintaining the intricate details and composition of the original.</derivativePrompt><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 11:49:50 EST</pubDate></item><item><title>The Two Fridas by Frida Kahlo (1939)</title><link>https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Two_Fridas.jpg</link><description>The Two Fridas is a powerful representation of dual identity and the emotional turmoil surrounding personal and political issues. Created during a tumultuous period in Kahlo's life, this painting showcases her exploration of identity and the conflict between her European and Mexican heritage. It is significant not only as a self-portrait but also as a celebration of femininity and resilience in the face of pain and heartache.</description><derivativePrompt>Create a new artwork inspired by The Two Fridas that depicts an internal struggle with identity, using vibrant colors and symbolic representations to express emotions.</derivativePrompt><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 11:49:14 EST</pubDate></item><item><title>American Gothic by Grant Wood (1930)</title><link>https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Grant_Wood_-_American_Gothic.jpg</link><description>American Gothic is an iconic piece of American art that epitomizes the Midwestern spirit during the Great Depression. Grant Wood's portrayal of a stern farmer and his daughter, set against a backdrop of a Gothic-style house, has been interpreted as both a celebration of rural American values and a critique of American life. Its unique blend of realism and stylized idealism captures a pivotal moment in American identity.</description><derivativePrompt>Create an artwork that reimagines the figures from 'American Gothic' in a contemporary urban setting, while maintaining the emotional expression of vigilance and resilience.</derivativePrompt><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 11:49:43 EST</pubDate></item><title>Daily Artwork Recommendations</title>
    <link>https://laratliff-dev.github.io/daily-art-rss/daily_art_feed.xml</link>
    <description>A daily exploration of influential artworks and creative inspiration.</description>
  </channel>
</rss>
